<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<BLOGS>
    <BLOG id="1">
        <TITLE>Rosetta Closing in on Comet</TITLE>
        <AUTHOR>
        NASA
        </AUTHOR>
        <PICTURE>
        resources/pia18516-cr_0.jpg
        </PICTURE>
        <TAGS>Rosetta</TAGS>
        <POSTDATE>June 19, 2014</POSTDATE>
        <UPDATEDATE></UPDATEDATE>
        <BODY>
            <img src="resources/pia18516-cr_0.jpg" alt="Blog photo" title="Blog photo"/>
            <p>Less than half the distance between Earth and moon separates Rosetta from its destination, comet 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko. The European Space Agency's (ESA) spacecraft will become the first to orbit a comet and land a probe on its nucleus. It is beginning observations and sending science data back to Earth.</p>
            <p>Recent images from Rosetta's Onboard Scientific Imaging System (OSIRIS) indicate that the comet is currently at rest -- no longer showing signs of an extended dust coma surrounding its nucleus. At the end of April, OSIRIS images revealed the comet was active -- spewing out enough gas and dust to create an extended coma. Upcoming images will offer even more information, as the comet is quickly covering more space in OSIRIS＊ field of view. Currently, comet 67P scales to about one pixel.</p>
            <p>※It will still take a few weeks before we can discern a detailed shape,§ said OSIRIS Project Manager Carsten G邦ttler from the Max Planck Institute for Solar System Research, Gottigen, Germany. ※But we are now no longer restricted to studying the brightness of the nucleus.§</p>
            <p>Launched in March 2004, Rosetta was reactivated in January 2014 after a record 957 days in hibernation. Composed of an orbiter and lander, Rosetta's objectives upon arrival at comet 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko in August are to study the celestial object up close in unprecedented detail, prepare for landing a probe on the comet's nucleus in November, and track its changes as it sweeps past the sun.</p>
            <p>Comets are time capsules containing primitive material left over from the epoch when the sun and its planets formed. Rosetta's lander will obtain the first images taken from a comet's surface and will provide the first analysis of a comet's composition by drilling into the surface. Rosetta also will be the first spacecraft to witness at close proximity how a comet changes as it is subjected to the increasing intensity of the sun's radiation. Observations will help scientists learn more about the origin and evolution of our solar system and the role comets may have played in seeding Earth with water, and perhaps even life.</p>
            <p>Rosetta is an ESA mission with contributions from its member states and NASA. Rosetta's Philae lander is provided by a consortium led by the German Aerospace Center, Cologne; Max Planck Institute for Solar System Research, Gottingen; French National Space Agency, Paris; and the Italian Space Agency, Rome. JPL, a division of the California Institute of Technology, Pasadena, manages the U.S. participation in the Rosetta mission for NASA's Science Mission Directorate in Washington.</p>
        </BODY>
    </BLOG>
<BLOG id="2">
<TITLE>NASA Statement on Successful Rosetta Comet Landing</TITLE>
<AUTHOR>
NASA
</AUTHOR>
<PICTURE>
</PICTURE>
    <TAGS>Rosetta</TAGS>
<POSTDATE>
November 12, 2014
</POSTDATE>
<UPDATEDATE>
</UPDATEDATE>
<BODY>
The following statement is from John Grunsfeld, astronaut and associate administrator for NASA＊s Science Mission Directorate in Washington, about the successful comet landing by the European Space Agency＊s Rosetta spacecraft:

※We congratulate ESA on their successful landing on a comet today. This achievement represents a breakthrough moment in the exploration of our solar system and a milestone for international cooperation. We are proud to be a part of this historic day and look forward to receiving valuable data from the three NASA instruments on board Rosetta that will map the comet＊s nucleus and examine it for signs of water.

※The data collected by Rosetta will provide the scientific community, and the world, with a treasure-trove of data. Small bodies in our solar system like comets and asteroids help us understand how the solar system formed and provide opportunities to advance exploration. We look forward to building on Rosetta's success exploring our solar system through our studies of near earth asteroids and NASA's upcoming asteroid sample return mission OSIRIS-REx. It＊s a great day for space exploration."
</BODY>
</BLOG>
<BLOG id="3">
<TITLE>Magical Minish Cap</TITLE>
<AUTHOR>
GaymerFox's Den
</AUTHOR>
<PICTURE>
/resources/minishcap_title.jpg
</PICTURE>
    <TAGS>Zelda, Minish Cap</TAGS>
<POSTDATE>
January 29, 2015
</POSTDATE>
<UPDATEDATE>
</UPDATEDATE>
<BODY>
It＊s not often that I get to dive into a retro title that I＊ve never had the chance to play before, but I got that rare opportunity with Minish Cap through my Wii U Virtual Console. Suggested by followers on Twitter (@Atari_Barbie and @Happy_Natto, I＊m looking at you guys), I finally decided to take this beloved classic for a well deserved spin. I＊ve reached a point in the game where I＊ve experienced nearly everything it has to offer, from the addictive Kinstone Piece collection and trading side quests, to the clever dungeons and well hidden secrets scattered throughout the overworld map.

Minish Cap reminds me in spirit of Link to the Past, but incorporates a lot of elements from Ocarina of Time, Majora＊s Mask, and Wind Waker (and probably other handheld Zelda games that I＊m not all too familiar with) like music, characters, and locations. I enjoyed running into the Gorons, Talon and Malon (and seeing the Lon Lon Ranch), Gorman, Beedle, the little boy with a perpetual glob of snot oozing from his nose, and other familiar faces from the Legend of Zelda universe. In almost every new location I entered, my ears perked up when hearing hints of familiar tunes 每 the Minish Forest echoes the Lost Woods from Link to the Past, and I hear the Dark World theme from the same game in the tune for Mt. Crenel. Two of my absolute favorite tracks from Minish Cap happen to be the Hyrule Village and Minish Village accompaniments.

While the progression of the game is pretty standard as far as most Legend of Zelda games go (i.e. you advance from one dungeon to the next in a linear fashion), there＊s a lot of other things you can do along the way in the form of Kinstone Piece collection and matching, the source of the game＊s sidequests that I mentioned earlier. It＊s not entirely novel in concept, but it＊s a cool feature in action 每 scattered all over the world are pieces of ancient relics, all split perfectly in two, with various citizens of the game holding matching halves. When you find someone who holds a Kinstone Piece that matches one of yours, you can join them together to cause something special to happen elsewhere on the map 每 doors open, water drains away to reveal hidden caves, chests appear, and more. The Pieces come in three colors 每 Green, Blue, and Red 每 with the Red ones unlocking the most important secrets. I loved seeing the results of each combination, and then seeking them out, which isn＊t too much of a chore since they are all conveniently marked on your map.

Of course, in addition to the Kinstone Pieces, there＊s still a lot of Heart Pieces to collect, and Link has a huge arsenal to discover, from the traditional Bow and Arrow and Boomerang, to spiffy new items like the Gust Jar, Cane of Pacci, and the Mole Mitts. My personal favorite is actually the Gust Jar, since it has so many uses. You can suck up dust and uncover secrets beneath it, defeat annoying peahats, draw in springy mushrooms to launch yourself over gaps, vacuum up pots and rocks, and propel yourself over water on lily pads. Compared to other Zelda games, I felt that this one was more ingenious in the way that it made you use Link＊s items.

Speaking of ingenious, one of the most important mechanics is Link＊s power to shrink to a tiny size and explore the world from an entirely different perspective. It＊s pretty cool 每 in your small size, you can see and speak to the Minish, enter small holes in walls and cracks in the ground, and explore tiny regions that you can＊t as your normal size. I love the dynamic it adds to the gameplay, and it makes me take a good look at every screen that I enter to see if there＊s anything I can access as mini-me.

It seems like there＊s still quite a bit for me to find even though I feel the game is soon coming to a close, but Legend of Zelda games tend to always surprise me with the amount of content included. I can＊t wait to finish it up!
</BODY>
</BLOG>
<BLOG id="4">
<TITLE>Mars Longevity Champion Launched 15 Years Ago</TITLE>
<AUTHOR>
NASA
</AUTHOR>
<PICTURE>
/resources/pia20331_01padig191.jpg
</PICTURE>
    <TAGS>Jet Propulsion Laboratory, Journey to Mars, Launches, Mars, Mars Odyssey, Solar System</TAGS>
<POSTDATE>
April 6, 2016
</POSTDATE>
<UPDATEDATE>
</UPDATEDATE>
<BODY>
The NASA spacecraft that was launched 15 years ago this week carried the name 2001 Mars Odyssey and the hopes for reviving a stymied program of exploring the Red Planet.

Back-to-back failures of two Mars missions launched in 1999 had prompted an overhaul of NASA's Mars plans. It worked: Not only has Odyssey itself operated successfully longer than any other spacecraft ever sent to Mars, but during Odyssey's lifespan so far, all six subsequent NASA missions sent to Mars have also succeeded.

A Delta II launch vehicle lifted Odyssey from Cape Canaveral Air Force Station, Florida, on April 7, 2001. When the spacecraft reached Mars on Oct. 24, 2001, it fired its main engine to enter orbit. A three-month "aerobraking" phase followed, using carefully controlled dips into the upper atmosphere of Mars to adjust the size and shape of the orbit in preparation for systematic mapping of the Red Planet.

The year of the launch and arrival played into NASA naming the mission 2001 Mars Odyssey as a tribute to the vision and spirit of space exploration portrayed in the works of science-fiction author Arthur C. Clarke, including the best-seller "2001: A Space Odyssey." Clarke (1917-2008) endorsed the mission's naming before the launch.

Odyssey completed its prime mission in 2004. With repeated mission extensions, it became the longevity champion of Mars spacecraft in December 2010.

"Every day for more than five years, Odyssey has been extending its record for how long a spacecraft can keep working at Mars," said Odyssey Project Manager David Lehman of NASA's Jet Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena, California. "The spacecraft is remarkably healthy, and we have enough fuel to last for several more years."

Lockheed Martin Space Systems, Denver, built the Odyssey spacecraft and collaborates with JPL in mission operations.

"In addition to the quality of this spacecraft, the careful way it is operated has been crucial to how it has stayed so productive so long," said Odyssey Project Scientist Jeffrey Plaut of JPL. "Odyssey was designed for a four-year mission. We're in the 15th year, and it keeps doing everything we ask it to do."

Some of Odyssey's important findings were accomplished within the first year after launch. One suite of instruments found evidence for water ice close to the surface in large areas of Mars. Another investigation measured the natural radiation environment on the way from Earth to Mars and in orbit around Mars, gaining information vital for design of human missions in what has become NASA's Journey to Mars.

Odyssey's longevity has enabled other feats, such as complete global mapping of Mars both in daytime light and in nighttime infrared emissions.

Each full year of changing seasons on Mars lasts about 26 months, so Odyssey has observed the planet through more than six Martian years. These observations have revealed some seasonal patterns that repeat each year and other seasonal events, such as large dust storms, which differ significantly from year to year.

Just in the past year, Odyssey's orbit has put the spacecraft in position to observe Mars in early-morning light. Previously, the spacecraft flew over ground that was either in afternoon lighting or pre-dawn darkness. Maneuvers in 2014 and 2015 were designed to alter the geometry of the orbit with respect to the sun. The new geometry enables studies of morning clouds and fogs and comparison of ground temperatures in the morning to temperatures of the same sites in the afternoon and pre-dawn.

In addition to its direct contributions to planetary science, Odyssey provides important support for other missions in NASA's Journey to Mars through communication relay service and observations of candidate landing sites. More than 90 percent of the data received from NASA's Spirit and Opportunity rovers has been relayed via Odyssey. Relay support for NASA's Curiosity Mars rover is shared between the Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter and Odyssey.
</BODY>
</BLOG>
<BLOG id="5">
<TITLE>Fish Can Sense Touch with Their Fins</TITLE>
<AUTHOR>discovery news</AUTHOR>
<PICTURE>/resources/dnews-files-2016-02-fins-can-sense-touch-160211-jpg.jpg</PICTURE>
<TAGS></TAGS>
<POSTDATE>02/11/16</POSTDATE>
<UPDATEDATE></UPDATEDATE>
<BODY>
A species of fish has been found to have touch-sensitive fins, along with cellular structures resembling those that are key to the sense of touch in mammals.

University of Chicago (UC) scientists, in a paper published Feb. 10 in the journal Proceedings of the Royal Society B, have found that the pictus catfish, a bottom-dweller from the Amazon River, has neurons and cells in its pectoral fins (the ones just behind the gills) that are extremely sensitive to touch.

These Fish Are Oddly Shaped For A Reason: Photos

"It was a surprise to us that, similar to mammalian skin, fish fins are able to sense light pressure and subtle motion," said UC graduate student Adam Hardy, an author of the study.

Using the flat end of a pin, and a brush, Hardy and his team stimulated the fish's pectoral fins and then measured the resulting neural activity.

They found that the fish's neurons responded to more than just the touch itself: They also conveyed information about the pressure being applied as well as the motion of the brush.

VIDEO: How Our Teeth Evolved From Ancient Fish

Meanwhile, cell structures in the pectoral fins, the scientists learned, resembled those that are crucial to sense of touch in mammals.

"Like us, fish are able to feel the environment around them with their fins," said UC graduate mentor Melina Hale. "Touch sensation may allow fish to live in dim environments, using touch to navigate when vision is limited."

"It raises a lot of exciting questions," she added, "on how sensory cells shape the brain's perception of environmental features, and may provide insight into the evolution of sensation in vertebrates."

Furthermore, the researchers think this sense of touch is quite common among sea-floor fish. "We suggest that touch-sensitive fins may be widespread in fishes that maintain a close association with the bottom substrate," they wrote.

Currently, the team is experimenting with other species of fish, to see if the same touch-sensitivity is present. "We predicted that touch-sensitive fins would be very useful for bottom-dwelling fish," Hardy said, "but you can imagine its utility in nocturnal or deep-sea environments as well."

These Fish Were Made For Walking: Photos

The researchers think the new findings could also aid in the design of future undersea robots that toil in dark environments.

"For example," offered Hale, "you can envision fish-inspired sensory membranes that can be used to scan surfaces in underwater environments where light may be obscured."
</BODY>
</BLOG>
<BLOG id="6">
<TITLE>Rare Pink Dolphin Might Be Pregnant</TITLE>
<AUTHOR>danny clemens</AUTHOR>
<PICTURE>/resources/pinky-banner.jpg</PICTURE>
<TAGS></TAGS>
<POSTDATE>09/09/15</POSTDATE>
<UPDATEDATE></UPDATEDATE>
<BODY>
Pregnancy rumors are swirling around one of the world's few pink bottlenose dolphins.

Affectionately named Pinky, the blush-colored creature was first spotted in 2007 in Louisiana's Calcasieu Lake by charter boat captain Erik Rue.

"It was absolutely, stunningly pink," Rue said in a 2009 interview. "I had never seen anything like it. It's the same color throughout the whole body. It looks like it just came out of a paint booth."

In the eight years that have since passed, Pinky has been spotted on multiple occasions, according to WGNO. It was only recently, however, that Rue said he witnessed Pinky engaging in mating behavior:


It's unclear exactly why Pinky is so brilliantly pink. Many believe that the dolphin is an albino, only 14 of which have been reported worldwide, according to the Washington Examiner. Some conflicting reports, however, suggest that she suffers from a genetic disorder.

Two other dolphin species -- the Chinese white dolphin (Sousa chinensis) and the Amazon river dolphin (Inia geoffrensis) -- are colloquially known as pink dolphins, although neither species is quite as stunningly pink-hued as Pinky.
</BODY>
</BLOG>
</BLOGS>